pgbrandsampler.ca 2010-06-16

# P&G Privacy Statement

| 

## Information We Collect

We may collect information about you from a variety of sources, including information we collect from you directly; information we collect about you when you visit our sites, use our services, or view our online advertisements; and information we collect about you from other sources (where permitted by law).

_Information we collect directly from you:_  
We collect information directly from you when you choose to participate in our offers and programs or otherwise provide information directly to us. The following are examples of information we may collect directly from you: 

  * Name, email address, postal address.
  * Username and password.
  * Phone number or mobile number.
  * Age.
  * Date of birth.
  * Other information about you and your family such as gender or product use preferences and/or behaviors.
  * Biometrics collected during volunteer consumer research studies (such as facial expression recognition, heart rate, and skin condition)
  * Demographic information.
  * Payment information (such as a credit card).
  * Future communication preferences
  * Contact information for friends you may wish us to contact. When you provide us information for these refer a friend messages, we use the information only to send the message you request.

_Information we collect when you visit our sites, use our services, or view our  
online advertisements:_  
We use cookies and other technologies to collect information about you when you visit our sites, use our services, or view online advertisements. The following are examples of information we may collect with these technologies: 

  * Your browser type and operating system.
  * Web pages you view.
  * Links you click.
  * IP address.
  * Site you visited before coming to our site.
  * P&G emails you open and/or forward
  * P&G offers or links you connect to via emails.

_Information we collect from other sources:_  
We may obtain information about you from other sources, including commercially available sources, such as data aggregators and public databases. The following are examples of information we may collect from other sources. 

  * Name, postal address.
  * Age.
  * Income level.
  * Marital status and number of children.
  * Your interests such as hobbies and pets.
  * Consumer and market research data.
  * Purchase behavior. 
  * Publicly observed data or activities, such as blogs, videos, internet postings, user generated content, and in-store shopping behavior.

**All of the information we collect about you may be combined to help us tailor our communications to you and to develop world-class products and services of superior quality. ******

|  Back to skip navigation menu   
---|---  
| 

## How We Use This Information

**To provide offers, products and services.** We use the information we collect to provide the products and services you request, to tell you about other products and services offered by P&G, and to manage our sites and services.

The following are ways we may use the information we collect about you: 

  * Send samples, premiums, products and information.
  * Develop new products and services.
  * Enroll you in contests, programs, or offers you request.
  * To provide you with other services that we have offered to you
  * Create and manage your account.
  * Process payment for purchases or other services.
  * Protect against or identify possible fraudulent transactions.
  * Where permitted by law, provide you with customized, unsolicited offers and information about P&G’s products and services through postal mail.
  * Develop and provide advertising tailored to your interests.
  * Analyze the use of our products, services, and sites.
  * Understand how you arrived at our site.
  * Determine the effectiveness of our advertising.
  * Enforce our Terms and Conditions and otherwise manage our business.

|  Back to skip navigation menu   
---|---  
| 

## Your Choices & Access to Your Information

_Choices_  
We give you choices about how we communicate with you. _Digital / Electronic Communications_ (examples: email, mobile).  
We only send you promotional mobile or email messages if you explicitly ask to receive these. (You opt in).  
You can stop receiving promotional mobile and email messages from a particular P&G brand or group by following the instructions provided in any such message you receive from that brand or group. _Postal Mail_  
Where permitted by law, we may mail you unsolicited offers or product information that we believe is of interest to you.

You can stop receiving promotional postal mail from a particular P&G brand or group. Promotional postal mail may contain opt out instructions, and you can stop receiving promotional postal mail from a particular P&G brand or group (such as Every Day Solutions, Envie de Plus, Zin in Meer) by following those instructions.

You can also stop receiving promotional email or postal communication from a particular P&G brand or group through this Privacy Statement. Please [click here](http://www.pg.com/privacy/contact_us/privacy_country_list.html "click here") to select your country and learn how to complete your request.

**PLEASE NOTE:** If you choose to stop receiving promotional messages from us, we will honor your request. However, we will continue to send you service related communications and we may need to keep the information we have collected about you for record keeping, analysis or other reasons, to the extent permitted by law.

_Access_  
We take steps to keep your personal information accurate. You can view, correct or update the personal contact information you provide P&G. Some P&G programs provide access to view or update personal information online. Check where you registered to learn if you can view or update your information there.

If information access and update is not available where you registered, [click here](http://www.pg.com/privacy/contact_us/privacy_country_list.html "click here") to select your country and learn how to access and update the personal information you provided P&G. P&G does not charge for this service and responds to reasonable requests in an appropriate timeframe. 

|  Back to skip navigation menu   
---|---  
| 

## Cookies, Web Beacons and other Technologies

Cookies. A cookie is a small file placed on your computer when you visit a site that can be understood by the site that issued the cookie. We use cookies to monitor how our sites are used and to help personalize your online experience. For example, when you register on our sites, we may store a unique code in a cookie on your computer. The next time you come back to the site from that computer, our servers use the cookie to recognize you. We can then use the information you provided when you registered combined with your activities on our sites to provide you advertising and offers of interest.

You can accept or decline cookies. Most browsers automatically accept cookies. To learn more about cookies, including how to refuse cookies on your computer, click these links: 

  * For Microsoft Internet Explorer: <http://www.microsoft.com/info/cookies.htm>
  * For Mozilla Firefox: <http://support.mozilla.com/en-US/kb/Options+window+-+Privacy+panel>
  * <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/cookies/>

Web Beacons. Web beacons are small bits of code embedded in web pages or in emails. We may use web beacons to deliver or communicate with cookies, to count users who have visited a web page, and to understand usage patterns. We also may include web beacons in e-mails to learn if messages have been opened, acted on, or forwarded.

You can disable the ability of Web beacons to capture information in this manner by declining cookies as described above.

Other Technologies. Examples of other technologies we may use to provide better service to you follow: 

  * **Web Session Variables.** Information that is passed from one web URL to another as you browse.
  * **Browser plug-ins/add-ons.** Additional web components that may need to be installed to enable certain web features on our sites. You have the option not to install these components.

Third-Party Advertising. We may allow third parties, including business partners and ad networks, to display advertising on our sites. Some of these companies may place a cookie on your computer to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement. This enables them to understand where you, or others who are using your computer, saw their advertisement and deliver ads that they believe are of interest to you. We do not control these companies’ use of cookies. Some of these companies are members of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI), which offers a single location to opt out of their cookies. Please visit the Network Advertising Initiative’s website at:  
<http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp>

How we use Cookies, Web Beacons and other Technologies. We use these technologies to provide you a richer and more personalized consumer experience. We do not store any of your personal information in cookies, web beacons or other technologies on your computer. For more detail see 

_“How We Use This Information.” ___ |  Back to skip navigation menu   
---|---  
| 

## Information Sharing

The success of our business depends on your trust, and we do not sell your personal information to marketers outside of P&G. We share your personal information only as described below and within P&G.

In general, we do not share personal information with marketers outside of P&G unless we have clearly asked for and obtained your explicit consent.

Third-party service providers. We rely on third-party service providers to perform a variety of services on our behalf. In so doing, we may need to share your personal information with them. Please note that we provide our service providers with only the personal information they need to perform their services and we require that they protect this information and not use it for any other purpose.

For example, we may rely on a service provider to: 

  * Fulfill your product and service requests and answer your questions.
  * Host our sites and deliver our email and mobile messages.
  * Mail product samples, contact contest winners, manage payments or take other actions on our behalf.
  * Analyze data, sometimes combined with other sources, to send more targeted communications to you.
  * Conduct research and analyze data to improve our products, services and sites.

 _In addition, where permitted by law, we may also rely on a service provider to:_  

  * Combine personal information about you that P&G has collected with personal information about you that our business partner has collected so we can jointly send tailored promotional communications to you. In such instances, our business partner will not have direct access to any information we share about you with the service provider, and only the service provider will be allowed to use the combined set of information to send you joint communications that we hope will be of interest to you. If you prefer not to receive these joint communications, you can always opt out by following the instructions provided in any such communication or through this Privacy Statement as indicated above
  * Perform other services that we request.

We provide these companies with the personal information they need to provide these services on our behalf. We require these companies to protect this personal information and to not use the information for any other purpose.

Other situations. We may disclose your personal information: 

  * If a P&G brand is sold to another company.
  * Where permitted by law, to protect and defend the rights and property of P&G (including enforcing our Terms and Conditions).
  * And when required by law, and/or public authorities.

Aggregated and non-personal information. We may share aggregated information that cannot identify you for general business analysis. For example, we may disclose the number of visitors to P&G sites or services.

|  Back to skip navigation menu   
---|---  
| 

## User Generated Content

Some P&G sites enable users to submit their own content for contests, blogs, videos, and other functions. Please remember that any information you disclose becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal, financial or other information in a submission. P&G cannot prevent such information from being used in a manner that may violate this Privacy Statement, the law, or your personal privacy and safety and is not responsible for the results of such postings. 

|  Back to skip navigation menu   
---|---  
| 

## Information Security

We are committed to keeping personal information secure. We have appropriate technical, administrative and physical procedures in place to protect personal information from loss, misuse or alteration.

We limit access to personal information to those who have a business need. We keep personal information only for a reasonably needed amount of time.

When we provide your personal information to our third party service providers we require those companies to protect the information and to not use the information for any other purpose.

When we collect or transmit sensitive information such as a credit card number, we use industry standard methods to protect that information.

|  Back to skip navigation menu   
---|---  
| 

## Information Transfer

Your personal information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in a country other than the one in which it was provided. This may include the US. When we do so, we transfer the information in compliance with applicable data protection laws.

We take steps to protect personal information no matter what country it is stored in or transferred to. We have procedures and controls as appropriate to help ensure this.

We adhere to the EU Data Privacy Directive and country data privacy laws, as well as the U.S. Department of Commerce [Safe Harbor Program](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/ "Safe Harbor Program").

|  Back to skip navigation menu   
---|---  
| 

## Children's Online Privacy

We believe it is important to provide added protection for children online. We encourage parents and guardians to spend time online with their children to participate in and monitor their online activity.

We do not intend to collect personal information from children under 13 online, except on some sites specifically directed to children.

When we do collect personal information from children, we do so in compliance with applicable country children’s data protection laws.

U.S. sites that collect information from children under the age of 13 are covered by a privacy statement that meets the requirements of the U.S. Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act. [Click here](http://www.beinggirl.com/en_US/pages/privacy.jsp "Click here") to read that Privacy Statement.

[Click here](http://www.pg.com/privacy/contact_us/privacy_country_list.html "Click here") to find out how to obtain a copy of the information your child has provided P&G, to update the information or instruct us to no longer contact your child

|  Back to skip navigation menu   
---|---  
| 

## Contact Us

If you have questions or concerns regarding your privacy, please contact P&G directly. [Click here](http://www.pg.com/privacy/contact_us/privacy_country_list.html "Click here") to select your country and be linked to the correct address or e-mail address to use, or use the postal address below. Please feel free to use your native language when sending your questions or comments.

Otherwise, you can contact us at this address  
**P &G Global Privacy Team**  
**PO Box 599**  
**Cincinnati, Ohio 45202 USA**

We are committed to working with you to obtain a fair resolution of any complaint or concern about privacy. We cooperate with country data protection authorities if they believe that a privacy problem has occurred.

We participate in the U.S. Council of Better Business Bureau’s (BBB) Accredited Business Program. Further information about this program and its dispute resolution process is available at [www.bbb.org](http://www.bbbonline.org/ "www.bbb.org")

For more information on how to help protect your computer, your personal information and your family online, visit our Personal Privacy Tips  
<http://www.pg.com/yourprivacy/index.shtml>

|  Back to skip navigation menu   
---|---  
  
## Changes to This Privacy Statement

We will post changes to this Privacy Statement and update the effective date when this Privacy Statement is updated. If we make any material changes to this Privacy Statement, we will notify you by sending an e-mail to the e-mail address you most recently provided us or by posting notice of the changes on this site.

Last updated: August 2008

**2008 Update**  
Clarifies that within P&G, the information you provide to one P&G brand may now be shared within the company across any P&G brand. This change allows us to (1) better tailor our advertising and offers to you and (2) tell you about all the products and services offered by P&G that we think may be of interest to you.

**2005 update**  
No substantive changes were made to the Privacy Statement. This update was to: clarify and simplify the content to improve readability; remove reference to specific advertising partners; add information about how to manage cookies, and to indicate the addition of a children’s privacy statement for certain U.S. websites.

**2002 Update**  
No substantive changes were made to the Privacy Statement. This update was to: clarify that a company that purchases a P&G brand may obtain information about consumers who had signed up for that brand; add examples of the types of third parties that P&G may share information with if consumers give us consent, change the name of the advertising partner; and clarify children’s privacy to be in line with local law, and to provide a physical address for our corporate offices. 

Back to skip navigation menu   
  
### Country Specific Information  
  
BELGIQUE

Conformément à la Loi sur la Protection de la Vie Privée du 8 décembre 1992, vous disposez d'un droit d'accès et de rectification de vos données personnelles. Vous pouvez également vous opposer à leur traitement. Le responsable du traitement de vos données en Belgique est la société Procter & Gamble DCE (Belgium Distribution Division) sprl.

Pour tout renseignement complémentaire, vous pouvez vous adresser à notre service du consommateur en Belgique: **Service du Consommateur, BP 81, 1090 Bruxelles.**

BELGIE

Overeenkomstig de Wet op de Bescherming van de Persoonlijke Levensfeer van 8 december 1992, heeft u het recht tot toegang en tot verbetering van uw persoonlijke gegevens. U kan zich eveneens verzetten tegen het houden van uw persoonlijke gegevens. De verantwoordelijke voor de bewerking van uw gegevens in Belgïe is de venootschap Procter & Gamble DCE (Belgium Distribution Division) bvba.

Wil u meer weten hierover, kan u contact opnemen met onze consumentendienst in Belgïe: **Consumentendienst, BP 81, 1090 Brussel.**

Back to skip navigation menu   
CANADA

Procter & Gamble Inc. complies with Canadian Federal and Provincial privacy laws and regulations including the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act.

Procter & Gamble Inc. will only use your personal information for the purposes intended and as detailed in the Global Privacy Statement unless we have obtained your consent to use it for other purposes. 

Residents of Canada are notified that the personal information they provide to Procter & Gamble is stored in the company’s databases outside of Canada including in the United States and may be subject to disclosure to authorized law enforcement or government agencies in response to lawful demand pursuant to the laws of that country.

If you need to contact Procter & Gamble Inc. regarding your personal information, then please write to the following address:

**S. Valkonen  
Privacy Officer  
416-730-4003  
Procter & Gamble Inc.  
4711 Yonge Street  
North York, Ontario  
M2N 6K8

E:mail privacyfeedbk.im@pg.com

**

Back to skip navigation menu   
FRANCE

Les informations que vous nous communiquez sont utilisées à des fins de prospection et de fidélisation et/ou pour vous faire éventuellement parvenir des informations sur nos produits ou ceux d’autres sociétés. Elles pourront être temporairement transférées hors Union Européenne pour qualification, hébergement. 

Vous disposez d’un droit d’accès, de rectification et d’opposition aux informations qui vous concernent. Pour exercer ce droit, contactez :

**Procter & Gamble France SAS   
163/165 quai Aulagnier - 92600 Asnières-sur-Seine  
E-mail : frconsumers@custhelp.com**

Back to skip navigation menu   
GREECE

Για περισσότερες πληροφορίες σχετικά με το ελληνικό νομικό πλαίσιο, μπορείτε να ανατρέξετε στον ν.2472/1997 και τις αποφάσεις της Αρχής Προστασίας Δεδομένων.

**ΠΡΟΚΤΕΡ & ΓΚΑΜΠΛ ΕΛΛΑΣ ΕΠΕ  
Λ.Συγγρού 165, 17 121 Νέα Σμύρνη  
Υπηρεσία Καταναλωτών: 0800 –23000 (χωρίς χρέωση)**

Back to skip navigation menu   
ITALIA

Ai sensi e per gli effetti del D.Lgs. 196/2003 sulla privacy, ti informiamo che, nel caso tu fornisca i tuoi dati navigando all'interno di questo sito, i dati medesimi potranno essere trattati, con mezzi elettronici,direttamente o anche attraverso terzi, per le seguenti finalita'

1\. effettuare ricerche di mercato e sondaggi, anche on-line;  
2\. inviare materiale informativo, pubblicitario, promozionale e/o commerciale, sia per via e-mail che via posta, relativo sia alla Procter & Gamble che ai suoi prodotti;  
3\. effettuare eventuale attivita' di vendita diretta;  
4\. effettuare comunicazioni commerciali interattiva  
5\. partecipare a giochi e concorsi

I dati potranno inoltre essere comunicati a societa' controllate, collegate e/o partecipate dalla The Procter & Gamble Company, o comunque facenti parte del gruppo Procter & Gamble in Italia e/o all'estero (anche paesi extra UE), nonche' a societa' terze che effettuino attivita' di trattamento dati per conto della Procter & Gamble stessa, fermi restando i livelli di sicurezza utilizzati per proteggerli ed i fini per i quali sono trattati.  
In nessun caso i dati saranno ceduti a Societa' terze per fini commerciali diversi da quelli della Procter & Gamble e dei suoi marchi senza il tuo preventivo consenso.  
In relazione al trattamento dei dati, potrai altresi' esercitare in qualunque momento i diritti previsti dall'art. 7 del D. Lgs. 196/2003, rivolgendoti a Procter & Gamble – Viale Cesare Pavese 385 – 00144 Roma

Back to skip navigation menu   
  
KOREA

개인정보 관리책임자 및 관련부서  
"P&G"는 이용자의 개인정보를 보호하고 개인정보와 관련한 불만을 처리하기 위하여 아래와 같이 관련 부서 및 개인정보관리책임자를 지정하고 있습니다. 

<개인 정보 관리 책임자>  
성 명 : 최 병 욱  
전화번호 : 080-023-3333  
E - M A I L : vmsmile.im@pg.com 

<"P&G" 고객센터>  
부 서 : 소비자 상담실   
전화번호 : 080-023-3333(수신자 부담 요금 전화)  
E - M A I L : vmsmile.im@pg.com  
문의시간: 오전 9시~오후 6시  
토요일, 일요일 및 공휴일은 휴무입니다. 점심시간은 12:00~13:00 입니다. 

13\. 개인정보 침해 관련 상담 및 신고  
개인정보침해에 대한 신고, 상담이 필요하신 경우에는 정보통신부 산하 공공기관인 한국정보보호진흥원(KISA)에 개인정보침해신고센터로 문의하시기 바랍니다. 개인정보침해신고센터  
전화 (02) 1336  
URL : [http://www.1336.or.kr](http://www.1336.or.kr/ "http://www.1336.or.kr")

14\. 정책변경에 따른 공지의무  
"P&G" 개인정보취급방침은 2001년 07월 01일에 제정되었으며 법령, 정책 또는 보안기술의 변경에 따라 내용의 추가, 삭제 및 수정이 있을 시에는 변경되는 개인정보취급방침을 시행하기 최소 10일전에 "P&G" 홈페이지를 통해 변경이유 및 내용 등을 공지하도록 하겠습니다. 

개인정보취급방침 버전번호: V2.0  
개인정보보호정책 시행일자 : 2008년 5월 1일  
개인정보보호정책 최종변경일자 : 2008년 4월 21일

Back to skip navigation menu   
NEDERLAND

Overeenkomstig de Wet van 6 juli 2000 houdende regels inzake de bescherming van persoonsgegevens heeft u het recht tot toegang, verbetering en verzet van uw persoonlijke gegevens. De verantwoordelijke voor de bewerking van uw gegevens in Nederland is de venootschap Procter & Gamble Nederland B.V.

Indien u hierover meer informatie wilt, kunt u schrijven naar:  
**Procter & Gamble Nederland B.V.  
T.a.v. Consumentenservice  
Postbus 1345  
3000 BH ROTTERDAM  
email adres: pgconsumentnl.im@pg.com **

Back to skip navigation menu   
PORTUGAL

Os seus dados pessoais serão recolhidos e inseridos pela **PROCTER & GAMBLE PORTUGAL – Produtos de Consumo, Higiene e Saúde, S.A.** (de ora em diante abreviadamente designada por P&G) num ficheiro automatizado para realização de actividades de marketing destinadas a pessoas com o seu perfil de consumo. O preenchimento dos dados é obrigatório. Caso pretenda vir a ter acesso aos seus dados ou deseje que os mesmos sejam rectificados, alterados ou eliminados deverá dirigir-se à P&G, Ed. Álvares Cabral, Quinta da Fonte, 2774-527 Paço de Arcos. Os dados recolhidos poderão ser transmitidos a outras empresas (designadamente, outras sociedades do grupo Procter & Gamble), sedeadas em Portugal ou no estrangeiro, para realização de actividades de marketing. Caso deseje opor-se a tal cedência deverá assinalar este campo [•]. Se não quiser que os seus dados pessoais sejam utilizados para receber outras comunicações de marketing, por favor assinale este campo[B1][B1] [•]. A recolha e o processamento de dados pessoais será sempre feita de acordo com a lei Portuguesa que seja aplicável e todas as autorizações que para o efeito se revelem necessárias serão previamente obtidas junto da Comissão Nacional de Protecção de Dados Pessoais. Nos termos legais, a P&G adoptou medidas para assegurar que os dados facultados sejam protegidos contra o acesso ou utilização por terceiros não autorizados. Todavia, a P&G chama a atenção para a existência de um risco residual de acesso não autorizado na internet. Para aceder à nossa "Declaração sobre Privacidade", por favor, 

_clique aqui:_ [www.pg.com/privacy/portuguese/privacy_notice.html](http://www.pg.com/privacy/portuguese/privacy_notice.html "www.pg.com/privacy/portuguese/privacy_notice.html") Back to skip navigation menu   
SPAIN

Sus datos serán incorporados a los ficheros de las compañías PROCTER & GAMBLE ESPAÑA, S.A. y ARBORA & AUSONIA, S.L.U. para informarle y pedir su opinión sobre ésta o nuevas ofertas relativas a los productos y servicios de las citadas sociedades y realizar estudios de mercado, a través de cualquier medio, incluso e-mail o SMS, así como para realizar tratamientos con el objeto de adecuar nuestras comunicaciones a su perfil particular. Asimismo, sus datos podrán ser utilizados por las empresas anteriormente indicadas para enviarle información relativa a terceras empresas relacionadas con los sectores de telecomunicaciones, ocio y gran consumo. Si desea acceder a sus datos, rectificarlos, cancelarlos, oponerse a su tratamiento o que los mismos no sean utilizados para ofrecerle información de las empresas anteriormente mencionadas o de terceras empresas, diríjase a PROCTER & GAMBLE ESPAÑA, S.A. (Avda. de Bruselas nº 24 28108 Alcobendas, Madrid) y ARBORA & AUSONIA, S.L.U. (Pg. dels Til.lers, 2-6, 08034 Barcelona).

 _Si no desea recibir mas información nuestra marque X en esta casilla_ Back to skip navigation menu
